Long ago, there was a witch
who lived in the forest.
She intervened in the war between France and England,
and used her power to end the bloodshed.
An unusual witch, indeed.
Her name was Maria.
She shared names with the Blessed Virgin,
and just like her, she was a virgin.
Familiars,
this is what the witch, Maria, desires—
Maria!
Let go of Lady Maria!
Next...
I'll aim for your head!
Children of God...
Your arrows will not stop me.
Stop it, both of you.
Do you know who this is?
It's Archangel Michael.
A-Archangel... Michael?!
S-Saint Michael...
Your bewilderment shows that you did not realize who I was.
God of heaven, please show him forgiveness for his sins.
Children of God,
why would you protect this witch, who ignores the orders of heaven?
But Saint Michael, Maria saved everyone!
She made medicine for my Grandmother,
and protected my father during the war!
Saint Michael! I wouldn't be here if it wasn't for Lady Maria!
And I'm not the only one,
she's saved countless others too!
In order to uphold the natural law of this world,
the witch Maria must be punished.
Punished...?
That is the will of the heavens?
Enough of this!
Anne, Joseph, run!
I-If that's the case...
I'll even... draw my bow against an Archangel!
In the spirit of "loving thy neighbor"...
We...
I...
love the witch Maria!
The heavens have let down a shower of blessings, to witches and the faithful alike.
The God of Heaven has reached a new decision.
The witch Maria shall be granted clemency.
But this time,
under no circumstances may she use of her magic amid the masses.
In addition, the moment you lose your virginity,
you will be relieved of your magical powers
as a way of atonement for your sins.
Huh?!
Ezekiel, come forth.
Ezekiel.
She will serve as my representative.
Witch Maria...
Balance your own happiness
against that of the worlds.
Maria!
Lady Maria!
Are you feeling any better?
I'm fine... Thank you.
What happened to the mercenaries?
They were—
handed over to Lord Provost.
The village is safe now.
I see...
That Michael...
And what was that about balancing?
You didn't understand?
This is why witches are...
So cute!
Who are you!?
It's Ezekiel.
This must be her usual form.
You should consider my words as if they were Saint Michael's.
Simply put, if you believe this world is in need of your magic,
then you should be prepared to sacrifice your happiness and pleasures to prove it.
Do you understand now?
Wait a minute!
Are you saying that if I lose my virginity, I'll lose my magic too!?
Exactly.
Forget it!
If that's the case, then I'll never...!
I should've thrown it away when I had the chance!
L-Lady Maria...
How deplorable. That's why witches are—
Ouch! Wait! What did you—?
Oww!
How dare you!? I'm Saint Michael's...
Stop it! Ouch! Hey! Ouch!
I... love the witch, Maria!
Ow! Ouch! Hey, stop!
Shut up! Stop ruffling each other's feathers!
It's just in our nature as owls.
It's Michael's fault for sticking a dove in an owl's nest.
Stop with all this nonsense!
Just get out there and give it up to the nearest pack of stray dogs so you can become a normal human.
What's the deal with, uh...
b-becoming a normal person as soon as I lose that?
That's not all.
If you try to use your powers in public, you'll have Saint Michael's spear thrown at you.
And its true form is...
Tou!
Ouch! Hey! Stop that, you familiars!
This pipsqueak is really pissing me off!
In human form, my powers
are far greater than yours!
Is that so?
Then how about I prey upon that twerpy body of yours?
Artemis doesn't need to do a thing.
I'll have this fledgling cooing all night!
I-I'm Saint Michael's...
Stop it, you two.
Don't you get enough of that with your nighttime jobs?
I haven't been able to do that yet!
You don't need to!
When are you going to give me what I'm missing!
I'd be fine with having my way with anything at this point!
Maria, you were with me when
we saw it on that rainy night!
You know, that guy's thing,
that looked like the serpent you summoned!
Thing!?
Thing?
Just put that thing you saw on me!
That thing was a masterpei—
Go do something you don't need a thing for, like making a meal to thank Anne and Joseph!
So, the rumor is true?
Witch Maria...
The next time she appears,
I'll have to inform Brother Bernard.
Bless us, Oh Lord,
and these thy gifts which we are about to receive from thy bounty,
through Christ, Our Lord.
Amen.
In the name of the Father, and of the Son,
and of the Holy Spirit. Amen.
Ah, I'm sorry, but this is quite common for us.
Hmph.
Say, Maria?
Are you a heretic?
Huh!?
More than a heretic, she's a witch.
I know that, but the bishop
said that heretics are evil.
He said that heretics usually have short hair, or expose their legs.
So what about that dove over there, then?
I'm part of the heavenly host.
I don't have to follow the rules of this world.
So what happens if Maria goes into a city?
No matter how you look at it, she's a witch...
...they'll burn her right away.
Like I care. I'll do whatever I want.
Not as long as I'm here.
With that appearance of yours,
you'll be treated the same.
I have powers, too.
No human can lay a finger on me.
Is that so?
Then why don't you go stop the wars?
Huh?
It's fine to bring peace as long as it's through
the church's power and not a witch's, right?
If that brings an end to all the fighting, I couldn't ask for more.
The heavenly host may watch the doings of the world, but we never intervene.
Lady Ezekiel...
Anne and I have never witnessed a France that wasn't at war.
I know the word "peace," but I can't imagine what it's like.
While I find it unfortunate that we can't expect help from the heavens,
I'm trying my best to understand.
But is it too much to ask for a sign, or an omen, or just words?
That's...
And, not even for a minute,
could I ever believe that Lady Maria's
actions should be considered evil, or worth heavenly punishment.
That's enough.
It's no use telling her that.
It's something that's already been decided.
Saint Michael did that to Maria...?
So, is she safe now at least?
Yeah. She looked much better after the meal.
This is for you, Grandmother.
She said to drink it if you're
feeling any pain where you were hit.
Is that so?
Say, Grandmother?
Hm?
Maria may be a heretic,
but she's not evil, right?
Forward, soldiers!
Send those usurpers tainting our
land back to their isle!
This fight's gonna be huge! Time to make gold, brothers!
You better make me rich, worthless Britons!
Genoese mercenaries, forward!
Here they come!
Don't let them get any closer!
Looks like it's begun.
I doubt many of them will be returning home.
Don't even think about it.
These actions were decided by people of this world.
Any interference by non-humans is forbidden.
I never said I was planning to interfere.
Then why did you come here?
Do not worry.
They are faithful children of God—
Shut up.
It's time to make some gold!
This is so contradictory.
Huh?
The heavenly host doesn't meddle in this world's affairs, right?
Cover me!
Here I go!
Well, my actions are part of this world too, so don't get in the way!
With God's divine protection!
Ezekiel!
I won't allow it.
Let's return.
There's no reason for us to be here.
This is infuriating!
Does Michael have his eyes on me all the time!?
Huh? Of course not.
Saint Michael is very busy.
He can't be keeping tabs on you all day.
Really?
That's why I'm here.
Now, let's get going.
Wh-What!?
A Tarasque!?
Did France's witch do this!?
Who cares!? Get the hell out of here!
Curse this english witchcraft!
Retreat! Retreat!
Hey, Maria!
You weren't watching, were you?
It just appeared out of thin air! Who could have done that?
Could it be Michael?
Am I... being taken for a fool?
Pull back, Galfa! That thing will send you flying!
Again!?
That goddamn witch!
Witch... you say?
Yes. I received word she appeared on the battlefield again.
What shall we do?
She has been quite the topic of conversation among the people lately.
There's been requests to the church for it's opinion of her.
May God's blessings be with you.
Thank you very much.
Everyone's hearts are being led astray.
And after all you've done for the people,
day in and day out, Brother Bernard—
That one...
Huh?
has helped the villagers once again?
Yes.
It seems that she received a warning by the heavens for doing so, and fled.
From what I heard, Archangel Michael...
I don't understand.
Huh?
What does she hope to achieve?
I don't know...
Let us meet this witch,
Maria.
I'm truly sorry.
Your usual attire is a bit...
I understand.
I'd rather not cause a scene anyway.
Thank you... very much.
I-It's not like you need to thank me for that.
So what does this monk want with me?
I haven't been told anything,
except to escort you there.
He must be an arrogant guy if he simply calls on a witch after taking the monk's vow.
I hear Sir Bernard is a very compassionate person.
I doubt that any conflicts will arise,
but if one does, I'll be sure to protect you.
W-Whose side are you on?
I turned my bow against Saint Michael.
What's going on?
It looks like a hog is being judged for trampling a person to death.
It is clear that this beast mercilessly trampled a person to death.
This court, under the blessing of God,
shall now pass judgment.
Guilty!
It is sentenced to death by hanging!
Huh!? But it's just a hog!
That's true, but a crime is a crime.
Hey, Joseph!
Sir Galfa!
What? You got a girl, too?
I was just escorting her to an acquaintance.
Good day.
Hi!
You're so dull.
C'mon, live a little.
Have you been drinking?
More like drowning!
Maria got in my way again!
Damn it! Not even get a coin for all that.
I'll starve to death before I ever die out there!
If it comes to that, I'm here to comfort you.
I'm sorry, but we're in a bit of a hurry.
We'll be on our way now.
Yeah, later.
Hey, girl!
Be sure to satisfy him for me, would ya?
Sir Galfa!
See you!
Um... I can't go further,
but he's waiting up ahead.
Huh? Oh, right. The monk.
I'm pleased to meet you.
My name is Bernard,
and I am in charge of this monastery.
I'm Maria, the witch.
And–
Quiet. You'll just make this confusing.
You have such a holy name.
May I ask who gave it to you?
I don't know.
I've been Maria since I was born.
From what I can imagine, you must have been baptized when you were young.
Is this supposed to be an inquisition? Do you think you can capture me?
Without an accuser?
No. That's not why I called you here.
This apple cider was brewed at our monastery.
Apple cider?
Please, if you will.
Do not worry.
Nothing has been added to it.
Bernard, was it? It's not like I have all day.
I'm willing to put in a good word with the bishop,
so would you like to have a confession?
Huh!?
That name of yours is most befitting for a faithful servant of God.
Are you kidding?
No. I am serious.
Your actions may be unorthodox, but you still have supporters.
If you act now, your sins can be absolved.
Of course, I can't overlook you calling yourself a witch.
But if you repent, you may walk alongside us as one who reveres our Father in the heavens.
The church will welcome you with a forgiving heart.
What's in it for me?
You will gain great love, and have a peaceful life.
Then, what do you folks get out of this?
We do not act out of self-interest.
We offer our hand to all who seek the love of God.
There's no need to hesitate...
You're right...
I'm a witch.
I don't give a damn about heaven or the church,
and I hate apple cider.
Give my regards to your "Maria."
Gilbert.
Yes?
Notify the abbot that I would
like to make a confession of sin.
Understood.
I have exchanged words with an unclean witch.
Ego Te Absolvo...
Witch Maria...
May your sins be absolved.
Lady Maria, how was it?
It was nothing, just small talk.
That was your chance back there.
That's how you saw it,
but I'm not about to be forced into something like that!
A peaceful life doesn't matter...
I absolutely refuse!
Bees lead such a wonderful life.
Under the reign of the queen,
all are equal and work daily without qualms.
I can see the beauty in a perfect society like that.
What... about the witch?
No action is needed.
Huh?
It takes time to collect honey.
For now, let leave the witch to her work,
for the good of the cities and villages.
We don't need to take drastic measures until she becomes a problem.
I see...
Do my actions seem like that of a nonbeliever?
No! Brother Bernard, you are thinking of what's best for the city!
Who would dare condemn you!?
Thank you.
Deus Caritas Est...
Everything is from God's love...
You should go speak to the church of this world again.
I don't want to.
If you have a problem with that,
go back to Michael.
I would if I could!
You...
Who's there?
I am not a who,
nor am I a what.
But I've been called Cernunnos.
Witch Maria...
What do you hope to achieve from your actions?
I've been getting that question a lot lately.
If something I don't like is happening
in front of me, I simply can't let it go.
That's all.
Whether you like it or not,
people cause conflict and eventually perish.
By the time you make a difference in this world,
the witnesses will already have passed.
And when new life is born, conflict starts anew.
All efforts to stop this are futile.
You would never find out unless you try!
Not that I will stop you...
After all, for me, it's simply the same pattern repeating itself.
I will watch you at leisure, Maria.
Wait!
Dirty... Dirty...
You're a virgin, right?
Let's go get rid of your virginity. Like, today.
T-Today!?