This was back in the days when the battle
against England was still ongoing.
There was a witch living near
our village who hated wars.
That witch would not curse
people nor do evil deeds...
...but instead used her powers
to put a stop to the fighting.
Her name was Maria.
She held the same name as the Blessed Virgin...
...and shared her virginal status as well.
So... it was you and the other one who
summoned a dragon to stop the warfare...
Artemis...
Please lay beside me tonight...
You're going to call for your forces to strike
against the French Imperial Army across
the bridge tomorrow night, right?
Honorable knight of England, Falstaff...
Yet you yearn 'For a woman on such a night?
I care for neither England nor
the Roman Catholic Church!
You are my king and my god, Artemis!
My adorable, foolish Christian...
Cry like a prostitute.
What is going on?
England was showing signs
of imminent attack this morning...
...and yet now they are fleeing in haste.
Le Comte Guillaume!
It seems confusion arose
among the enemy ranks!
Those leading the force are calling out
the name of Artemis as if possessed...
Artemis.--? Diana of Rome'?
It's Maria!
Does the merchant leader know something?
Maria is the witch who lives around here.
These are the doings of
Maria's familiar, the succubus!
Wait, her name is Maria?
How dare that witch?!
Regardless, unlike previously,
we were saved this time.
I was prepared to retreat with news of delay
from the Duke of Bourbon's aid, but...
Lord in the heavens, forgive me
for giving thanks to the witch...
No.
This is also by the will of God.
Rather than giving thanks to the agent of heresy
tainting the name of the Blessed Virgin...
...-burning her at the stake
would be much more befitting!
So cold...
Maria.
Maria!
Ma-ri-a!
What insolence, calling upon
the name of a witch in such ease!
Huh?
It's me, Ann!
Ah, Martha's granddaughter.
Thank you, Maria! Father returned yesterday!
Huh?
Oh, that...
So, here's a gift!
A gift...?
Yes, a gift!
What?
I got it at mass.
They said this bread is a
part of Lord Jesus' body!
Why don't you attend, Maria?
No. I don't want to.
I really like Saint Margaret!
Do you want me to talk about her?
No thanks.
Really? Well, I think most
everyone else likes Saint Michael.
Maria, do you like Saint Michael?
I hate him.
They say he's scary, too.
But Saint Michael watches over
all of us, all the time, everywhere.
He isn't watching over us,
he's just keeping watch.
You know... a kid like you shouldn't
be coming to this kind of place.
And...
...no matter how often you pray, the angels
won't protect you from bandits or wolves.
Well, the angels aren't really
going to appear to protect us.
Divine protection is...
Um...
Well...
Just a minute...
Y-You're...
Huh?
Good morning, Lady Maria.
You sure have gall, coming here!
Huh? Well...
You knew I hated wars, and yet
you went to the battlefield!
Um... The flowers...
Ah, th-this isn't anything! Nothing at all!
Huh...
Well, I just came to say that I have
returned to my duties at the manor.
Thank you very much for saving us back then.
Hm? Oh, uh... You were there?
Not that I knew about it.
Are you Maria's friend?
Friend? Why, of course not.
Then you're her lover?
Listen here! He's just the messenger
for Le Comte Guillaume!
And as 'Far as this "friend"
thing goes, the witch Maria is...
What was that?!
Oww... Missed my landing...
What in the world are you doing?!
Come now, I was working
all last night without rest.
My hips are taking a hit, see?
M-Mind your manners!
That's an odd thing to say to a succubus.
Um... We'd like to excuse ourselves...
Oh, is that so?
Ann, give my regards to Martha.
Yes! I'll come again.
“Again?
--Until next time.
Right, next time...
Maria, weren't you angry with Joseph?
You know, for what he did
despite agreeing with you.
Th-That aside, how did things go?
I massaged them enough to deplete
their reserves for ten years.
OM)!"-
Hm? What?
There was a guy who was beyond my reach...
Active, aren't we?
Didn't expect someone to be ahead of me.
Wh-Who are you?!
I'll make you cry like a prostitute...
Huh?
Sire...!
Do not fret.
She must be the familiar of a witch
contracted by the King of Bourges.
Females are filth.
With the form of pure love that we embrace...
...there is nothing this familiar can do but leave.
Ah, dear Sire!
Oh, my dear Benjamin...
Homosexuality is in vogue now!
Say, Maria? Let's make an incubus, too.
--Huh?!
--A male demon.
There's no need for one.
Don't tell me you can't make... a man.
Because you... haven't seen it before?
Oh, come on, hurry and
get rid of your virginity!
Your unfathomable innocence
is really becoming a hassle!
Shut uuup!
It's a clumsy male that was lost in the woods.
Pretty much fit to become
an incubus, don't you think?
See? He's saying that he wants
to give thanks by doing his best.
Hm...
Just make him to 'Fit your fancy.
You know, like Joseph.
Well, but that's...
He's asking if that's impossible t-o do.
Impossible?
Nothing is impossible for me!
The witch Maria shall grant you your destiny.
Brethren of Lir, the wanderer
of the fields of night...
Join me as my familiar,
incubus, devourer of fertility!
Oh... Not bad at all.
Owl. Your name shall be Priapus henceforth.
Yes!
Hm?-f?
Hm...
Maria?
One of his key features as an
incubus is a bit hazy, you know?
That's because I haven't seen one
of them before... It's embarrassing...
"Priapus," my ass! You no-good witch!
Stupid virgin!
Shut up!
Follow me!
I'll just show you some guy's thing!
No! I don't want to!
Then I'll teach you so you can put one on him!
No! No!
Urn... So what am I supposed to do now?
Ahead is the fort where the
rabble soldiers of Bourges dwell!
In the name of our majesty, the wise
King Henry, king of England and of France...
...we shall destroy the enemy!
England doesn't have the military might,
but the mist is siding with them.
If their advancement to the fort isn't noticed,
their surprise attack may prove successful.
If so, we Valkyries shall lead
those who perish to Valhalla.
Hm?-f?
Wh-What's that?!
It... It's a Cyclops!
--The eye! Aim 'For the eye!
--Shouldn't we rather retreat?!
Sire...!
Show no 'Fear! Forward!
If you're not going to stop fighting,
prepare yourselves!
L-Let me do something, too!
You don't need to do anything.
Go back home ahead,
and prepare something to eat.
Th-That's not "Fair!
My, oh m)'-
What's she going to do
with that half-baked incubus?
That witch again, I see.
She is quite something, summoning Cyclops.
Let's see how much longer
her selfishness will last...
Urrh... It's so cold.
Busy, aren't we, working day and night?
Tell that to Priapus.
He's adamant about doing this.
I'll show you how good I am as an incubus.
Even if I'm not in full form, I can
easily soften up any ladies around.
Well then, hurry and get it over with.
Inside is the lover of the
commander occupying this city.
Nothing to it! Leave it to me!
Hm...
Good evening, my dear...
Like a prostitute, you shall...
“Huh?
"Hm?
Oh, my, are you the rumored demonic cutie?
Ah, I'm sorry, I made a mista...
Wha--'?! Whaaat?!
U-Um, I believe this person is a homosexual!
H-Hello?!
I'm so sorry!
You cry like a prostitute!
--Nooo! Forgive meee!
I don't have one of those on me!
It's fine as long as you have a hole!
--Nooo!
--Is this going too far?
This is the least he can do.
Come, dearie, you're supposed
to be an incubus. Come at me.
Artemis, take my place! Artemis!
Oh, what the hell...
My dear, do you like girls?
Oh, my, a succubus, too?
I'm sorry, but I hate outdated women like you.
Bring me someone younger.
Or else make this cutie do
the work he's supposed to do.
Work.
Artemis, that's a bit too...
This fulfills all three of your desires.
Enjoy...!
A-Artemism?!
Now... Who's going to do me first?
What?
Hey. look!
A serpent?! That must have
been a sight to see, then!
Don't you move, Artemis!
I'll douse this place along
with you in a sea of fire!
Come on, bring it!
Maria! Behind you!
Wha-J!
Serpent!
Michael...?!
Must be a warning.
Come on!
Just when I wanted to work as an incubus...
Of everyone, it had to be the Archangel...
You've been attracting too much attention.
I just hate fighting, that's all!
--Maria?
--What?
It looks like Martha and Ann's village is on fire.
Famished mercenaries
turned marauders, it seems.
How dare they do such a thing
in front of the witch, Maria?!
Um, are you sure it's safe?
You just received warning
from Archangel Michael...
With the world this beautiful...
...why are the hearts of people so foolish?
That village was the first village
to have ever accepted me.
Yahweh created the world in six days,
and then took a day to rest.
Yahweh should have worked one extra day...
We are the soldiers of the King of France...
...blessed by God, our majesty, King Charles!
Though we were working with the
forces of England a short while ago!
Mother...!
It's fine. It will all be fine...
The bishop will do something about this.
Ch-Chief... M-My load's been
killin' me! S-So, please...
Heh... Go ahead!
Yes! The chief gave us the go!
We can take them girls!
Hey! So that's all of 'em in the village, right?!
Wh-What?!
Sir Captain! This isn't what you promised!
Ahh?! So what?!
We got another one that was hiding!
--Grandmother!
--Ann!
What a letdown! It's just a hag!
Saint Margaret...
Saint Michael...
Ahh?! This door isn't opening! Let's burn it!
Village and all!
Saint Margaret...
Saint Michael...
Maria...!
Foolish marauders!
You shall pay for your sins!
Who the hell are you?!
Is... Is it you, Maria?
Fear beset you, so you never
lay siege to this village again!
Taranis!
Drive forth from this well upon your wheel,
and with the thunderbolt you hurl...
...burn the tainted eyes of those armed!
Urgh! What?!
L-I can't see...!
Ann!
Grandmother!
Ann?
Could this be...?
It's Maria.
Maria! It's Maria!
Maria...
Maria... Thank you, but please,
return to the forest.
If you use your magic any further...!
Michael...?!
T-Taranis!
I said those who wield arms!
Burn Michael's eyes, too!
In the name of Michael, servant of the
Almighty Father, God, I command you.
Ancient one, return t-o t-he darkness of the past.
Maria?
Is that... Saint Michael?
Huh?
You're all cowards!
All those on earth are praying for salvation!
And yet, none of you come to give it!
That's why I'm the one
trying t-o do all the saving!
Two hills beyond here, a village
is being marauded by bandits.
In the far east, a fortress is under siege...
...and in the city to the north,
eight innocents were burned at the
stake by the church of this world.
Why do you not save them?
You do it!
Isn't that what the church
of the heavens is for?!
The church of the heavens
keeps watch over the world.
We stop those like yourself to maintain order.
Mercenaries attacking cities is
the natural law of this world...
...and me stopping that disrupts order?
Exactly.
Behold...
Damn it...! My eyes!
--I can't see! I can't see!
--Help me!
M-My eyes are burning!
Wh-What?
They're the only ones blinded by the light?
Ah! Damn nag! I pulled a muscle!
Is anyone around?! Get me up!
Will you blind the eyes of the villagers next?
Halt, everyone!
Those blinded will not
be able to see for awhile!
Bind their hands and feet,
and remove them to afar!
Do not mar yourself with meaningless sins!
When their eyes heal, they will
likely attack another village.
Maria left?
Men of the village...!
Let us listen to Maria,
and throw down our arms.
The prayers of people are not requests.--“.
...nor are they commands.
All are actions of the world.
The heavens do not mediate in such matters.
You simply cannot bear seeing
what you hate in front of you.
That brings disorder to
the natural law of this world.
You're not convincing me!
What's wrong with that as my reason?!
If everyone did that, there would
be no fighting in this world!
Everyone?
That is called arrogance, witch.
Yes, I'm a witch.
I don't need to be preached to by an angel!
Archangel Michael...
Hope I can beat him...
Winds of Nerthus!
Let me go, scum!
Damn it!
Ann, go inside the house.
Maria went home to the forest already.
Who are you?!
I am a servant of the lord of this land!
Ah, he's the one that was at Maria's place...
While heading to the forest, I saw smoke
from the village, so I came to assist.
I saw lightning and light, but is
the witch, Lady Maria, here?
Joseph!
Are you sure we didn't need to be with her?
Fighting isn't our forte.
Fighting should be...
Wh-What?! We changed back!
This happens sometimes
when Maria's tired, but...
Tired...'?
Hm?
Maria!
What's going on?
M-Michael?!
I will rid you of your power as a witch.
This is mercy...
Wind of Nerthusm!
That is of no use, witch.
Or do you desire to ascend to the heavens?
I didn't do anything bad!
I see. Well, then...
Michael! Wait a moment!
Please let Maria go!
Familiars...
This is what the witch, Maria, desires...
Maria!
Let go of Lady Maria!
Next...
...I'll aim for your head!
I'm with the church of the heavens.
From what I heard, Archangel Michael...
All are in futility...
May your sins be absolved.