The Middle Ages, Northeastern France
Mother, do witches really live in places like this?
Supposedly...
Even though we've just entered the forest
I've already lost sight of the village.
Don't worry.
Just keep praying to Saint Margaret for protection.
O-Okay.
After all,
your grandmother has always returned home safely.
I'm sure the witch Maria is a kind person.
E-Excuse me, is anyone home?
It's so dark.
I don't think she's home.
I can hear you just fine.
You're Martha's daughter and granddaughter, right?
Yes, my name is Anne.
Anne, is it?
Martha's being very inconsiderate, isn't she?
It's not as if she's too weak to walk.
Well, Grandmother's feeling ill.
That's why we came on her behalf.
You have a lot of spirit.
Go on and take it.
It's the usual medicinal concoction.
Maria, you really are a kind witch!
But I wonder why...
the bishop said that witches are evil, indecent, and corrupt—
Mind your manners, Anne!
I-I'm so sorry!
Don't worry about it.
Villages used to respect witches for our magic and medicines.
Now, about the bishop's words, let's see...
The Roman Catholic Church isn't short on enemies, so...
Enemies?
I suppose you're too young to understand.
Can I become a witch too?
Wh-What are you saying!?
Why a witch?
Well, I could make Grandmother medicine,
and I could use magic to help my father when he's hurt.
Has something happen to your father?
Father is going to war.
By our Lord's decree, we have to send soldiers from our village.
Father was chosen to be one of them.
People get hurt when they go to war, right?
But if I could use magic—
You're not fit for that.
After all, you are one of the church's sheep.
Besides, magic isn't something that can simply be taught.
I see.
Therefore, I'll watch over him for you.
Huh?
With magic.
If he still gets hurt, just bring him here.
I'll prepare medicine—
Thank you!
You're such an amazing witch, Maria!
Amazing! Amazing!
You bet I am!
I'm not like those other witches—
Huh?
Eh?
That was so far!
I'm going to be bow-legged for a week!
Huh?
Ah, if it isn't Martha's daughter and her kid.
I heard you were coming to get medicine.
That aside, what are you wearing?
I'm home, Maria.
Maria was so cute!
Wasn't she? There was no reason to be scared.
Can we visit her again?
Well, she is a witch...
Hey, you damn owl!
It's Artemis.
It's important to give brats the right first impression!
My image should be revered by all!
So that's what this was for?
Yes!
You disguised yourself and waited for them the whole time?
Lots of free time, huh?
Shut up!
You know it would've been a waste of time.
Martha would've blown your cover as soon as they return home.
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
Say, Maria?
I'm hungry.
Fine.
Hax pax max Deus adimax turbidus!
In the first place, you took too long!
I finished all my tasks yesterday.
You and I do things differently.
I know you wouldn't understand, but my work takes quite a bit of time.
Well, I did ease the tensions of everyone at the commander level.
The battlefield to the south is already at peace.
You didn't take any lives, did you?
If a succubus goes too far...
We're not waging a war, right?
Don't worry. I'm not like the others.
I only milked them enough
to keep them moaning my name for the next month while rubbing one off.
Milked?
Uh, r-rub what?
Wait a second, my jaw is killing me.
I must of used it too much.
Jaw? Why your jaw?
Oh? You're curious today, aren't you?
In that case, would you like a detailed report, Master?
Maybe next time.
I need to go and pick up the arrows outside.
Maria?
Hm?
You reek of sweat.
Just eat and go to sleep!
Ah, that's right!
There's another war up north, and—
Must be puberty.
Good morning, Lady Maria.
I came bearing more requests.
More?
Hasn't there been a lot of these lately?
If you wish for a battle to end, write it down and send it into the forest.
A witch will bring an end to it with her powers.
It looks like the rumors of you have even reached the enemy forces.
There's English arrows here too.
Enemy?
It's not like I'm siding with France, you know?
I just hate seeing all these battles happening in front of me.
Right.
You know, the French Army must have a lot of nerve
to send messengers to someone they brand a heretic.
About that...
What?
As of today, my duties as my lord's messenger are over.
I've been conscripted as a soldier, to partake in the war.
I will go to regain control of England's position located up the Loire, for passage to Calais.
A brat like you, who doesn't know a thing about girls,
is going to go off and fight in some stupid war?
You're an idiot.
It's my duty...
A hermit living in the forest once told me of peace,
of a true utopia, where there is no fighting.
I was told that nothing would be better than a life without conflict among people.
One day, that world...
Maybe your actions will make that world a possibility, Lady Maria.
As a witch, you may not care to hear this, but I want to say something important.
Deep down, I really desire to continue visiting you,
rather than go off to war.
Please forget that.
Be careful.
Some of your superiors know that you've been coming to see me, right?
Well, yes.
At times people will sell others for their own sake.
So if you are ever questioned,
tell the Church I manipulated you, in order to gain their forgiveness.
M-May I have the grace of your hand?
What?
Ah, your name?
What was it?
It's Joseph.
Farewell.
Come again—
It's nice to know Maria is doing well.
And she was really cute, too!
But...
But?
Maria was saying that the Roman Catholic Church has enemies and things.
What does that mean?
Who knows?
Even Grandmother Martha doesn't know?
Nevermind that, what about your errand for your father?
Oh, that's right!
Ah, I'm sorry!
Maria...
Hm, but why?
Why her jaw?
I depart at sunrise.
If something happens to me, rely on the village elders.
I'm sure they'll help you.
Really, why you?
Why do you have to go to war?
It can't be helped.
I don't want to go, but this is still my duty.
If only we could afford to pay out your levy.
If I survive, I'll be back soon.
Father!
I made this!
It's a charm that Grandmother taught me!
Thank you, Anne.
I have nothing to be afraid of with this.
Be a nice girl, and listen to what the others say.
I'll be fine! And Maria will be protecting you, Father!
The Blessed Virgin?
No, the one in the forest.
She said she'll protect you with her magic!
Anne, that Maria in the forest, people call her a heretic.
You mustn't speak her name in public, you hear?
It would be a hassle, should the priests hear you.
But, she said she would protect you.
Puny Britons! I'll crush them!
That's right!
Villon! Everyone's waiting for you!
I know! I know!
Hurry up!
War...
Lady Maria, what would you...
Hey, Maria, shouldn't I be going out tonight?
I'm sure it's fine.
I told Anne to bring her father to me if he gets hurt.
Well, that too, but what about the other one?
Huh?
You know, that boy, Joseph.
Ah, well he said that the battle—
Wait, how do you know his name?
I-I'm sorry. I'm not used to this.
No, I should have been paying attention.
More importantly, could you give me a hand—
The hell you doing!?
Th-Thank you.
You've got some nice gear. You a vassal?
Ah, no. I'm just borrowing these.
Huh, so this is your first time in battle?
Yes.
Don't be falling during the battle
lest you'll get in the way of us making gold.
I'll be careful.
You're an odd one, acting polite to a mercenary.
Is that so?
Uh, we should return to our positions.
Ah, that's right.
May we go on ahead?
Do what you please.
There's no need for you to ask me.
Ah, we'll go on ahead, then.
The name's Galfa.
Make sure you pay me back later!
Yes!
My name is Joseph!
Someone you know, Galfa?
More like, "someone I used to know."
He's as good as dead out here.
Both sides seem to be pretty calm.
My succubus did pretty well, too.
Hey, I don't think we've met.
Where are you from?
If you'd like, you can join our guild.
I came from Winchester.
Aw, so you're from England.
Winchester? You mean like Henry Beaufort?
Is he still kicking?
I don't care where the gold comes from.
I have to say, you French witches are so prudish.
Instead of using your succubus, you should have some fun yourselves.
Children of God!
Even if you have neither shield nor helm, with the divine blessing of our Lord,
the cross shall lay waste to the heathens!
Lord, please...
Lord!
As usual, it seems.
Aren't we too close for this?
Children of God! Even in the face of the demonic Englishmen,
forget not, the divine protection of Saint Martin!
I knew it was too close...
Here we go!
You bastards!
Blessed Virgin Maria, please pray for our sinful ways, from now to the end—
Get up! Stand!
Hold no fear! God's divine protection is on our side!
Forward! Forward!
The Red Arm Routiers are moving in!
All right!
Don't let the spoils get away!
I wonder if Father's doing all right.
I'm sure he's fine. Maria said she'd protect him, right?
If so, there's nothing to worry about.
Maria has never broken a promise, ever.
And he has the charm you made him, too.
Yes!
Don't come near, Gallia!
That bastard.
Wait, did he...?
Hurry it up!
I know, Yvain!
Hey, England's forces are starting to fall apart.
Too bad for you!
I'm not on England's side.
I don't care which side I work with, as long as I'm paid.
With God's divine protection!
This is for earlier!
Come on, start walking.
Be sure to pay your dues to the Red Arm Routiers.
The lmperial Ordinance Cavalry?
They must be after the best of the spoils.
That bog should slow them down,
so we'll have to grab as much as we can first.
Where's our gold hiding!?
Would you like to be ransomed off as a prisoner,
or would you rather die here?
Lower your blade.
You may take me as a prisoner.
Heh. You got it.
He's gold to us! Treat him well!
Was I able to pay you back?
You...
Shit! England's coming back!
Anne, I'm sorry.
Just... Just once more.
I...
I wanted to see you,
Lady Maria.
Wh-What's that!?
What? Could it be...?
Looks like she came after all.
Oh, come on. It was just getting interesting.
Say, who's coming?
Heed my warning!
Huh?
Heed my orders, soldiers of the battlefield.
All who are within my sight.
Lady Maria...
Cease your fighting!
Ancient foe of Saint Marcel of Paris
answer the call of the witch of the hearth
and appear before me now!
Have any here bore witness to a dragon before?
No! But, now you shall!
D-Dragon!?
Dragon! We're not the same as those who destroy heretics.
Don't bring harm to any of them, you hear?
Run!
Anne, don't go asking favors from such a terrifying witch!
I hate battles!
And with that established,
I won't go easy on anyone who resists!
Aw, there she goes again.
Doesn't she understand that she's ruining all our succubi's hard work?
Right?
Hate... battles?
That was close.
If the knights had charged into battle,
we could have won.
When Maria appears, things always get muddled.
Damn it! What's with that witch!?
We weren't finished making gold!
Right!?
Thank you, Lady Maria.
So, why'd you come here all of the sudden?
I thought you were going to watch over Anne's father from afar.
I may be a witch, but I'm still pretty cute.
Huh?
There was a guy who thought
that joining the war was more enticing than me.
I'm here to teach him a lesson!
Huh? That's...
He's the only person who has ever kissed my hand!
But according to human rules—
Yet he looked happy!
You know what?
That's only because you asked him for his name!
But he k-kissed me!
On your hand!
Just because you're a virgin, that doesn't give you the right to push your values onto others.
How ironic.
All this chaos was caused by a witch
who is the embodiment of Christian teachings: a pure untainted virgin.
You're such a pain.
How about making a confession at church?
What are you saying!? The Roman Catholic Church is full of people who're scared of women!
Do you know what they did to La Pucelle, the girl who rose to save France!?
They jammed their fingers inside her to see if she was a virgin,
used her, betrayed her,
and burned her to death at the stake!
Just you see!
One day, they'll canonize the girl they treated like a witch as a maiden of patriotism!
I won't lose to that kind of Roman Catholic Church!
That's why that had nothing to do with virginity!
I'll give it up any time to anyone! It could be a dog for all I care.
In other words, you're finally at that age where you've become interested in that.
Hm? What?
Maria...
watashi wa ai wo shitta
I've learned of love's meaning
daken no mure ga hashiru yoru
I watched the mongrels running through the night
tsuki mo kokoro mo michite wa kake yuku
The sight made me shine as bright as the moon
dareka no shimei to watashi no seigi ga
The choice between my mission or justice
dilemma ni makareta
had left me in a dilemma
ikuhyakunen aruki tsuzuke
For hundreds of years
ashimoto no hana ni mo
I simply passed over the flowers surrounding me
kizukezu ni ite sashikonda rinkaku
until I noticed a silhouette cast in light,
sore wa anata no hikari
and it happened to be you
tomaranai shoudou wo sora ni mukete sakebitsuzuketa
I couldn't help but shout toward the heavens
kotowari ga ryouhou someru sekai de
Justice is the treatment this black world needs
watashi wa ai wo shitta
I've learned of love's meaning
anata no ikiru asu no tame ni
For the sake of protecting our loved ones,
futari de orokamono ni narou yo
let's become fools together
koko wa kami no hakoniwa ja nain da
After all, we aren't in God's Garden
Come with me! I'll show you what a guy's thing is like!
Good evening, my dear.
Divine protection is...
Why are the hearts of people so foolish?